The stars are going.
The planets who disappeared never barely
enough of us left to give the end a name.
The quiet rapture
Supplies dwindle.
Infrastructure crumbles.
Too few to rebuild.
Too many to feed.
Humanity decays.
I don't despair my sons.
I tell you now that there is more
to these moons than meets the eye.
The consolidation, they hide
their technology, their people.
They won't tell you what they found.
But I will.
One moon stands apart from the rest.
And in the darkness of that moon.
An ocean of blood.
Including the descent.
Mission blocks started.
Exploration of 85 on the road.
How's it looking down there, convict?
Ready to do some good for a change?
Yeah.
Let's get this done.
Roger that.
Cruising depth in roughly ten minutes.
Stand by.
I'm seeing some voltage
irregularities on the
instruments that keep
an eye out for sparks.
Flames are anything like that.
Flames.
Why would there be flames?
You do test this thing, right?
Hey, what is it exactly you want me
to find you haven't told me what it is
Hey, um.
Hey, are you hearing this?
Hello?
Hey.
Hey, you said not to go into the red.
We're in the red.
You can't be serious.
Fuck me.
Thank you.
Maybe.
Hey.
What do I do if I find
something not in the map?
You're not just pretending
you can't hear me, right?
Huh?
What's going on?
I'm done!
So just bring me back
up and throw me in prison!
I'm not doing this!
Tell me, if there's a problem, stop
because you fell, the heart could be
punctured, which means a leak, which
means flooding, which means you die.
Mom.
She's gone.
I don't know.
It seems fine.
Good.
I can't see much, but it seems like
the hall is in one piece, so we're going
to check on your progress while we
wait for the ocean to settle back down.
Hey, do you think we can get any pictures?
I mean, you could get
a couple won't, maybe?
Well, it might take a while
to settle, so go ahead.
Uh, settled.
What does that mean?
Is that why everything was shaking?
Essentially, yeah.
The bottom is an exactly rock.
Just, players have
controlled blood and gas.
But why would I say it wasn't stable?
I've seen a skeleton before.
How stupid do you think I am?
We're pulling you up.
Stand by.
So, uh, it's supposed to deal.
Am I done?
I'm here after that.
See you at least?
Uh, uh, yeah, I'm down a way.
But, yeah, maybe there might be a leak.
There was some blood dripping in.
And then there's some kind
of liquid building up in the walls.
It's just a conversation.
I know a common six shit.
Look, it doesn't matter.
You just warn the next person
that goes down what I found.
There's something alive down there.
Hey, yeah, so I found something good
We downloaded the pictures.
She'll look like a skeleton to me.
I said, come on, give me out of here.
I can't.
Like I said, you're welded in.
You can't get you out here.
We might miss the opportunity.
Another slip might go
somewhere that we can get.
So I'm going to give you
something to take example.
Hey!
You're not listening to me.
There's something else.
OK.
It's not like I don't
want the deal, all right?
I want the deal.
I want to make the deal.
It's not worth it.
It's not.
It's not worth it for me.
It's not worth it for you.
You're not finding this
skeleton, but you're not
hearing me when I say
there's something else.
Something alive.
There might just be.
We're gonna put this
on the stuff right up front.
All you gotta do is point
you in the right direction.
One that makes contact should be able
to grab onto something and hold onto it.
This is what am I
supposed to do, just ram it.
Pretty much.
You can't be serious.
I am.
You'll have to hit it hard, too.
Hard enough to make
sure that it catches you won't
be able to see if it works
for the second chances.
So you don't just want me to ram it.
You want me to ram it at full speed.
What the gage?
Why go through all this trouble?
If you want me dead so bad,
why don't you just do it yourself?
This is the best we have.
And it's a lot more than you deserve.
This is bigger than any
of us, so just do your job.
My job.
My job?
Oh, I'm sorry.
The handcuffs must have confused me.
I didn't realize this was voluntary!
Back!
Do walk away?
Is this someone?
Do you want us to go down there?
Go down!
Come back and get on free!
That was the deal!
How many times are you gonna
use me before you let me go!
Oh, good.
You can hear me.
Now, get someone else
for your suicide mission,
because I'm not going
to do that to the radiation.
You can't go in and fuck.
What?
It's not normal.
Camera and passing through blood,
so you need passwords to get through.
It's on.
I didn't know that.
No.
Look, I'm sorry, but maybe if you would
talk to me, this wouldn't have happened.
Just get the sample.
Drop him.
Come on, Captain.
Can I get you a damn set?
Can I have a fair plan after what you did?
I'll show you so, Rive.
Who is this?
Where's the other one?
He didn't think it was important to tell
me that your camera was a radiation gun.
That shit would happen at all.
This is bigger than us.
So I've heard it.
This is important.
The moment stage was a bad loss, but
imagine if we could actually rebuild it.
Even you could be a part of that.
I read your report used to
render it until fully by Ian's bullshit.
Will it talk about the last tree?
It's not about the tree, right?
Well, he didn't give me a tattoo.
The COI maybe burned it off.
I didn't choose either of them.
I still get a scar.
Since the choir rapture,
none of us get a choice.
There's a way to find
the way we get it real.
To the captain's attic, it's all a day.
It's a stick of the rest of the choir
rapture, but she cares about her crew.
I'm somewhere in those,
but you know, you're right.
Can you at least tell me if this
thing is blasting me with reading?
No, what the hell is it going to be?
you you
Thank you.
This is not an explanation.
It's an execution.
And they put you in here.
They don't want you all to return.
And even if you do, and even if they keep
their promises, what freedom waits for you?
A few dying ships and a sea of dead stars.
If there is still hope,
it lies beyond the veil.
Hope, in this void, is as
illusionary as the Starlight.
I will choose to breathe my last,
here, at the bottom of an ocean.
I will get my freedom.
Sorry, brother.
But I want to live.
Where'd you go?
Hello?
Can you hear me?
Uh, well, this is going to sum it up.
The skeleton's gone.
The skeleton is gone.
I don't know.
I'm at the coordinates.
It's like a picture.
It's just a big hill.
I don't know.
Maybe it got buried.
Uh, one second.
No, it's just more ill.
It's... How about now?
Yes, I am on a hill.
There is no skeleton.
Why is this so hot in here?
Can I not ask a question?
I...
I didn't mean for that to happen.
I was just...
I was scared.
The radiation.
I know what you mean.
Not that was.
Yeah, it won't cause us that.
Tell that to the other poor
bastards you left down here.
What's the point of lying to me?
What's the point of any of this?
What does it matter if you
find a big fucking skeleton?
This is all just useless
bullshit to get me killed.
Do you think I enjoy this?
Do you?
There aren't enough of us
left to be throwing lives away,
but there is too much at stake
not to take calculated risks.
Eden doesn't understand that.
You don't understand that.
What's on the stand?
It's all over.
That's what Eden understands.
At least they're not deluding
themselves with some big
future for humanity if we
all just believe hard enough.
It's game over and you know it.
Is that why you destroyed filament station?
That wasn't...
that wasn't supposed to happen.
That wasn't supposed to happen.
This.
The skeleton.
It moved.
Yeah, I'm looking at it right now.
I'm telling you.
It looks like something...
I don't think gas bubbles do this.
Yes, I see the skeleton, but
I'm telling you something's wrong.
It's just the head.
So I get this and I'm done.
You're not just gonna kill
me as soon as I get up there.
We need your help, and you're
earning your place in the consolidation.
That's all.
I'm sorry about the radiation.
I didn't know.
Have you been apologized to my tumors?
Just get the sample.
Fair enough.
How hard do I need to hit this thing?
I...
I don't know.
This isn't exactly the standard procedure.
Just ram it.
Get the job done.
Ship can handle it, I promise.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
All right, okay.
All right, yeah, it's his friend.
It's his friend.
And then I'm free.
Uh...
I ran it.
Did you get it?
I think I got it one second.
Uh, yeah, I'm looking at, um, I
mean, what might be a hole in the jaw?
I think I got it.
Is that it?
With all the buildup, I thought there
might be something a bit more calamitous.
Uh, there was something else.
There was something else
who was looking right at me.
I can still see them.
Stop saying they're gone.
We can all see them.
My son.
Those stars are already dead.
Mirror Ghost Light.
Growing dimmer by the day.
How?
What are this old time?
back.
Fuck that.
All righty.
God pin for you.
Almost worked.
all rich all rich all rich all rich
Oh, Rick.
Fire.
All rich.
Ah.
Thank you.
I'm fucked.
Sure.
Good.
Don't mind me.
I'm just trying to go home.
Just...
just pretend like I'm not even here.
I'm sure they're falling over
themselves trying to find me, so.
.. if you see anyone
looking for Simon...
Tell them I'm still alive.
I said, wait.
Hey.
What are you doing down there?
Hey, that's a joke.
This is weird.
The next door is over.
Eight running diagnostics.
Wait.
On the trail, you fail.
You fail.
You change the black
box from covering program.
You should be able to
choose the area immediately
or surrender yourself
to council authority.
the area immediately or surrender
yourself to council authority.
It's a vision privilege
for the area immediately
or surrender yourself
to council authority.
It's a vision privilege for the area
immediately or surrender the fucking authority.
It's a vision privilege
for the area immediately
or surrender yourself
to council authority.
You can't do it.
Not my problem.
Only one left to try.
I'm gonna see.
Come on.
Yes.
Come here.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm here.
Can you not hear me?
I can hear you.
Who are you?
This is the mother drink.
Who is this?
Who do you think it is?
It's not you.
It's not right.
Yeah.
You're not on the totion.
What?
What did you say?
You're still here, right?
I love that.
If you just stuck down there too.
I thought I was...
Look, they're still there.
I talked to them.
I know the radio's been spotty,
but they've made contact before.
Like, we could just be out of range.
Like, maybe we just
need to get hold of them,
and then they could send
someone down to meet us.
I'm together.
I'll start the last one.
Run last time.
Well, that's not enough.
You like my kid?
I'm trying to control your breathing.
Um, can you just...
Can you just keep talking to me?
Cause...
I just... Oh.
What would be the point?
You'll just run out of air faster.
Maybe that's for the best.
Some of the others went that way.
All the rules fade down here.
Action.
Actually, I don't want to talk anymore.
You might still have
time to talk to me again.
Of.
I don't know the danger of this place.
We have to warn them.
We can't die down here.
I don't want to talk.
What are you even talking about?
It's what caused the quiet rapture.
Or a fragment of it at least.
What?
You actually found something?
Does that mean you know what happened?
Is that how you're still alive?
Yes.
No.
I don't know if this isn't right.
I'm feeling something important.
We shouldn't be talking about this.
You've no reason you're
supposed to be forced on here.
You don't know, and it's better that way.
Forget about the light.
It won't help you.
And you can't help us.
Some things are too dangerous.
I think I have a concussion, or something.
If it's not CO2 buildup,
my head's out, right?
I just want to know what happened.
And you're still alive,
so I don't know if there's
a backup system, but
just give me something.
Hey, can you still hear me?
Please.
I don't know if you're just my imagination.
I don't know what's real anymore.
I've been losing track of time and...
I've been seeing some things.
Look, I just really needed
to be real right now, okay?
I just want to live.
Is that so wrong?
Why isn't anybody else more glad?
If everyone had eaten to skin?
You know, no, not even wants to
think this way, but what's more likely that
every planet and star disappeared or
that a few space stations disappeared?
Isn't it easier to believe that there's
still there wondering where all of us went?
Is it even more likely?
Is it happened?
Why can't it happen again?
Because it's in here.
Well, I have... just...
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't...
There's no backup systems, sir.
This piece is shit.
They wouldn't put a CO2 scrubber in this.
They wouldn't put a backup tank.
There's an old deposit down here.
This is the end.
And I'm wasting my breath
talking through a phantom.
There's never there to begin with.
Would you give everything just to survive?
Yeah.
I never had anything to begin with.
On one six, five to zero.
We will see the answer together.
And you will live.
And we will be free.
Deal.
OK. OK. OK. 116520.
If that's where you are, then
they knew you were here.
Maybe they were hoping
that I would find you.
Hey, we're still looking for us.
Maybe.
Yeah.
OK.
I'm on the way.
I'm about, um, 3, 8, 6, 14.
Not far, I think.
It's, uh, we don't lie.
I'm not about this.
It's everything.
So what is it?
What could possibly be
that important down here?
Do you believe in God?
Let's not get into that.
I hear enough of that kind of talk on him.
In God, he's a sliver of our
universe through a pinhole and thinks
it understands all that is
and all that will be and it will.
And why is that?
Because our God makes
sense of what it's here.
It should be.
What does it even mean?
The light could illuminate, and it
lies, it thinks, and therefore we are.
You know, if your
miracle could solve all their
problems, they would
just send me down again.
Why wouldn't they want to save you?
The knowledge and skill fade every year.
The same as the stars.
They blame me for what happened.
I was the only one trying to stop you.
Blaine you.
For what?
Film and station.
The blame.
What happened?
The filament station.
Yeah, I am.
Yeah, I really don't want to talk about it.
For what?
The filament station.
It's gone.
How do you not know?
The filament station is gone.
Yes.
It's gone.
Just like everything else since the choir
rapture, so what is it fucking matter?
What do you care?
Why is anyone?
I knew you'd do it as an office.
You think this was fair?
I didn't blow up film and station, but
the ones who did aren't getting punished.
Just me.
I didn't get a choice.
I just threw this short
straw and then I traded
one fancy metal box
to Diane for another.
While people that I thought
were my brothers, imagine me!
They abandoned me!
Just like they abandoned you.
What does he matter if we need up?
Probably not there.
I can't get to the surface, and neither
can you so what's the fucking point?
That is gonna go home.
Where are you?
I think I'm in the wrong place.
I didn't even tell you my name.
Yes, you did.
We will see.
We will know.
Shit!
Butcher!
Stop fucking with me!
Who is this?
I don't know what to say.
No.
No, I'm done.
I'm done?
I'm done being fucked with him.
I really was broken.
I broke it.
You can't tell me they drew you.
I don't even know how you survived.
I am... Hello?
Hello?
What did I do when I was in the hangar?
What?
No, no.
How many people were in the hangar?
I don't understand.
I told you how many
people give me a number.
Three, three, three.
You took a picture.
Yeah?
You blasted us with radiation.
No.
You're lying.
No, I'm not.
Can't be talking to me.
I'm the other.
What?
It's not possible.
What's wrong?
Convict.
What's my name?
This isn't helping.
What?
Tell me my name!
Say my name!
I don't think we ever got your name.
You smell me down here to die
and you don't even know my name?
We didn't send you.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, look, it's been days
since your last contact.
You should have run out of oxygen by now.
How are you still alive?
I'm not sure.
It says I have one light left.
I really don't know.
I don't know.
I thought I died.
I'm my nickname.
I don't know, I don't even know where I am
I, um...
I, uh...
I think I would have done enough, and...
God...
I would really...
I would really like to not
be done here anymore.
Please.
I know.
I don't think that's possible.
I had nothing to do with film and station.
I swear.
That wasn't part of the plan.
I made it in listening to you.
I'm really sorry.
It's not a matter of want right now.
No.
We can't risk any more times.
But what about the mission?
What about everything I learned?
What about the state of both reasons
I came down here in the first place?
You need that, right?
It's not worth the risk.
A bone fragment isn't
going to tell us anything
that we haven't already
seen with our own eyes.
This isn't about your past.
It's not punishment.
And I know it's not fair.
But our new orders are told and absurd.
So, after everything I've been
through, just coming down here.
Has anyone ever made it up?
Yes.
Did you know their names?
You know, I remember what he said.
We said I was the first one down there.
I was thinking about it when I was
looking at the wreck of the other ship.
You left down here.
The S-M-8.
I almost didn't notice the
name when I came out of
the big fucking hole on
this side, but... S-M-8.
Did he just say... Did you say S-M-8?
How do you know about that ship?
Right.
It had letters on it.
It can read.
You found the SN8?
Yeah, I did.
And not only that.
When I found it, the
computer it connected to it.
But it was downloading something.
Something about it.
Something about a black box.
An archive, right?
I'm right, aren't I?
Well, if you want, it, you gotta
come down here and get it.
That's fair.
I went through hell, but I came back with
something a lot better than a piece of bone.
If you want to, you have to
give me, you know, that's fair.
If there's no way that you're computer
downloaded, anything you don't have the right
credentials, that computer shouldn't even
be active without us giving you the login.
I'm not lying.
There was a note someone
told me to splice the wires.
And I know big secrets out.
I'm not the first one down
here, but this is what you need.
Isn't this what you wanted?
Come on.
I'm not lying.
I saw it.
I fell in the cave and I went down.
I navigated through it
and I found this ship.
There was still power.
The computer connected to it.
It was trying to download.
I'm telling the truth.
How far are you from it right now?
I mean, not far.
Thanks.
OK.
If I give you the right credentials
for a computer and you did actually
find the estimate, then you should
be able to download all of their data.
OK. We put power
redundancies into the black
boxes for just that
reason in case you know.
Yeah.
But be tell me.
If I do this, you get me out.
If you do this.
I'll get you myself.
And you're lucky I'm not
sending you down there instead.
Convict, you said you mapped it.
Do you have the coordinates?
When the line broke, I landed off the
map in some kind of fucked-up cave.
I don't know.
But this ship was the last thing I found.
About 725.
Maybe 500.
It was right next to the
only way out I could find.
And that was some...
I spent me out around 3.80, 6.15.
All right, here's the plan.
We'll get prepped on our end,
and if you can make it to the SMA
and back out, we can meet you
outside the entrance in 30 minutes.
But I'm serious.
You've got to be there in 30
minutes, or I'm gone, understood?
Yeah, I understand.
Um, so how do I get the files?
Go to the computer.
Press Control, Alt, Shift, Nine.
You should see a window pop-up,
username, admin, password, all caps.
7, X, 1, 1, F, 2, 6, A, 3, 1, 1.
Control shift what?
I'm in.
Okay.
30 minutes in and out.
If you miss the window,
you miss your chance.
But if we could pull this off, there was,
oh, for the CUI, for Eden, for everyone.
Nothing else matters compared to this.
But if you're not there,
you're not going home.
30 minutes.
I can do that.
It's easy.
I just go in and out, and
then all of humanity saved.
And then I'm free.
And then you're free.
Deal.
By the way.
One.
My name is Eva.
Simon.
Now let's get this gun, Simon.
David, hold your hand out of medical.
Tell him I need one last world.
I've been assigned to
carry out your pennies.
I'm honest, any other
captain would have had you
killed on site, so you should
consider yourself lucky.
I still love you.
If 62 others didn't make
it out of filament station,
I know that doesn't
include your compatriots.
I believe it.
We're all dead anyway.
Now, didn't want them to die.
Excuse me?
What did you just say?
When did you grow a conscience, Simon?
You got the highest
body count out here, killer.
Now, one of us has more
blood on their hands than you.
This purpose yet, at least.
Simon the butcher lost his nerve.
You're gonna have to kill
your own brothers to stop this.
Your words are not my butcher.
I wasn't moving there.
I'm just the guy that told
you they're crossed the wire.
The consolidation and also in
their secret must bear these burdens.
These hardships is anger.
We are the keepers of Eden.
We must help them.
Oh, Simon, don't be with him.
I don't have it.
You'll love it there.
I can't talk about any confiscates them.
They're hoping to start a
garden with their own subject.
Our duty is not done.
The last tree's dead.
What?
The last tree will live again.
It's Eden's grave.
When the last sun, the moon,
enjoying the growth, there will be a doubt.
I think that there's no soil, but we know.
We know that when we die,
our bodies become the soil.
How about we just stay
focused on the mission?
No, once you're down there,
you're going to be on your own.
It's true.
You'll have to navigate
the ocean for carefully.
It's right behind you.
You're not as current.
Even things might change.
You're a little different
once you're down here.
It's still there.
Thank you.
Okay.
I don't know, but what
am I supposed to say?
I'm always a track of being afraid.
I might have recorded this already, eh?
He's a hundred more.
I love that the pressure
mom found me so sad.
I don't know.
I'm supposed to hold you.
I know what, he's...
He's not good for you.
I don't think we should.
It shouldn't be possible, but...
I don't know what that means.
I think it was being aligned.
It's a... One, one, six, five, two, zero.
We only saw it with the samples.
We took from here.
A ghost, a quiet friend.
It's goodbye to me, nothin'.
I've been without the ability
to study further, we can only...
Uh, we went in.
I want to free for care.
It was everything, and we
saw, we saw the answer.
We love to fight us.
We need to see it.
The answer is right there!
You and my father!
We need to see it!
Ava, I'm here.
I think I'm sick of something.
I need you to get something
from the crossmates.
Trust me on this, there's
something down there.
Do you need to keep safe, okay?
No matter what, you
need to get in there safely.
Do you understand?
Here is if I swim through hell.
You are the only one that can.
Everything is true.
She can't.
What are you waiting for?
We had a deal.
Not everyone gets to be saved.
You talkin' about, you said you'd
give me how to hear that was the deal.
Please, it's time to please, listen to me.
It's worth it.
You deserve your freedom.
And I'm sorry.
That I can't give that to you.
But it's worth it.
It is more than me.
It's more than you.
It's bigger than you.
I'm sorry.
You're just a piece of shit, but
it doesn't even know it's dead.
What do you know?
No, let it know.
Fuck that!
Fuck you!
You want me, please?
Thank you.
This is the only one.
Get everything!
Shit!
There's a line!
All right, I'm your side!
I'm going to go to the next one.
you you